<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.lucasvittor.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.lucasvittor.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2022-07-05T03:22:59-03:00</updated><id>https://www.lucasvittor.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lucas Vittor Blog</title><subtitle>The place where I share my learnings.</subtitle><author><name>Lucas Vittor</name><email>lvvittor@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">270 Bits of Unsolicited Advice</title><link href="https://www.lucasvittor.com/270-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="270 Bits of Unsolicited Advice" /><published>2022-06-28T00:41:00-03:00</published><updated>2022-06-28T00:41:00-03:00</updated><id>https://www.lucasvittor.com/270-bits-of-unsolicited-advice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.lucasvittor.com/270-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/"><![CDATA[<p>Here is my personal collection of the best <a href="https://twitter.com/kevin2kelly">Kevin Kelly’s</a> unsolicited advices from all his posts.</p>

<h2 id="103-bits"><a href="https://kk.org/thetechnium/103-bits-of-advice-i-wish-i-had-known/">103 bits</a></h2>

<ol>
  <li>Don’t ever work for someone you don’t want to become.</li>
  <li>When you lead, your real job is to create more leaders, not more followers.</li>
  <li>Productivity is often a distraction. Don’t aim for better ways to get through your tasks as quickly as possible, rather aim for better tasks that you never want to stop doing.</li>
  <li>The biggest lie we tell ourselves is “I don’t need to write this down because I will remember it.” <em>(That’s the reason why I write this post)</em></li>
  <li>Speak confidently as if you are right, but listen carefully as if you are wrong.</li>
  <li>Three things you need: The ability to not give up something till it works, the ability to give up something that does not work, and the trust in other people to help you distinguish between the two.</li>
  <li>Half the skill of being educated is learning what you can ignore.</li>
  <li>You cannot get smart people to work extremely hard just for money.</li>
  <li>We tend to overestimate what we can do in a day, and underestimate what we can achieve in a decade.</li>
  <li>It’s possible that a not-so-smart person, who can communicate well, can do much better than a super-smart person who can’t communicate well.</li>
  <li>Backups are cheap compared to regrets.</li>
  <li>When you are stuck, explain your problem to others. Often simply laying out a problem will present a solution. Make “explaining the problem” part of your troubleshooting process. <em>(<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rubber_duck_debugging">Rubber duck debugging</a> is that you?)</em></li>
  <li>Don’t bother fighting the old; just build the new.</li>
  <li>You are as big as the things that make you angry.</li>
  <li>If you repeated what you did today 365 more times will you be where you want to be next year?</li>
  <li>Copying others is a good way to start. Copying yourself is a disappointing way to end.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="99-bits"><a href="https://kk.org/thetechnium/99-additional-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/">99 bits</a></h2>

<ol>
  <li>Under-promise and over-deliver.</li>
  <li>Be governed not by the tyranny of the urgent but by the elevation of the important.</li>
  <li>Don’t create things to make money; make money so you can create things. The reward for good work is more work.</li>
  <li>Train employees well enough they could get another job, but treat them well enough so they never want to.</li>
  <li>A multitude of bad ideas is necessary for one good idea.</li>
  <li>Most overnight successes —in fact, any significant successes— take at least 5 years. Budget your life accordingly<strong>.</strong></li>
  <li>To be wealthy, accumulate all those things that money can’t buy.</li>
  <li>It is much easier to change how you think by changing your behavior than it is to change your behavior by changing how you think.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="68-bits"><a href="https://kk.org/thetechnium/68-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/">68 bits</a></h2>

<ol>
  <li>Always demand a deadline. A deadline weeds out the extraneous and the ordinary. It prevents you from trying to make it perfect, so you have to make it different.</li>
  <li>A worthy goal for a year is to learn enough about a subject so that you can’t believe how ignorant you were a year earlier.</li>
  <li>Don’t be the smartest person in the room. Hang out with, and learn from, people smarter than yourself. Even better, find smart people who will disagree with you.</li>
  <li>The more you are interested in others, the more interesting they find you. To be interesting, be interested.</li>
  <li>Separate the processes of creation from improving. You can’t write and edit, sculpt and polish, or make and analyze at the same time. If you do, the editor stops the creator. While you invent, don’t select. While you sketch, don’t inspect. While you write the first draft, don’t reflect. At the start, the creator’s mind must be unleashed from judgment.</li>
  <li>Before you are old, attend as many funerals as you can bear, and listen.</li>
  <li>How to apologize: Quickly, specifically, sincerely</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Lucas Vittor</name><email>lvvittor@gmail.com</email></author><category term="english" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here is my personal collection of the best Kevin Kelly’s unsolicited advices from all his posts.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.lucasvittor.com/270-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/still_life_with_dead_game_fruits_and_vegetables.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.lucasvittor.com/270-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/still_life_with_dead_game_fruits_and_vegetables.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hack-ITBA: A hackathon with great people</title><link href="https://www.lucasvittor.com/hack-itba-a-hackathon-with-great-people/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hack-ITBA: A hackathon with great people" /><published>2022-04-02T12:38:00-03:00</published><updated>2022-04-02T12:38:00-03:00</updated><id>https://www.lucasvittor.com/hack-itba-a-hackathon-with-great-people</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.lucasvittor.com/hack-itba-a-hackathon-with-great-people/"><![CDATA[<p>Some weeks ago, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/javier-mermet">Javier Mermet</a> (a fellow data scientist and software engineer) and I participated in a team of two for the 36hs <a href="https://hackitba.vercel.app/">HackIT-BA Hackathon</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/ieeecsitba?s=21&amp;t=6hKXokZQaHabJFAEMxs2kw">ITBA Computer Society</a>.</p>

<h2 id="what-great-people-really-means">What great people really means</h2>

<p>I usually don’t participate in hackathons: they tend to be pitch-only, work-free, and with 3hs of sleep max. But this was different (except for the work-free and sleep part 🥲). The jury was top-tier and tech-oriented:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Matias Woloski (<a href="https://twitter.com/woloski">@woloski</a>), Co-Founder/CTO (<a href="https://twitter.com/auth0">@auth0</a>)</li>
  <li>Santiago Siri (<a href="https://twitter.com/santisiri">@santisiri</a>), Founder (<a href="https://twitter.com/proofofhumanity">@proofofhumanity</a>)</li>
  <li>Esteban Ordano (<a href="https://twitter.com/eordano">@eordano</a>), Co-Founder (<a href="https://twitter.com/decentraland">@decentraland</a>)</li>
  <li>Mariano Mayer (<a href="https://twitter.com/gugamayer">@gugamayer</a>), Co-Founder (<a href="https://twitter.com/newtopiavc">@newtopiavc</a>)</li>
  <li>Lucas Lain (<a href="https://twitter.com/lucaslain">@lucaslain</a>), Co-Founder (<a href="https://twitter.com/exactly_finance">@exactly_finance</a>)</li>
  <li>Agustina Fainguersch (<a href="https://twitter.com/agusfagus">@agusfagus</a>), Managing Director South America &amp; Miami (<a href="https://twitter.com/meta">@meta</a>)</li>
  <li>Santiago Valles (<a href="https://twitter.com/srvalles">@srvalles</a>),  Director of Software Engineering (<a href="https://twitter.com/itba">@itba</a>)</li>
  <li>Gabriela Macagni (<a href="https://twitter.com/gabrielamacagni">@gabrielamacagni</a>), Board of directors (<a href="https://twitter.com/ternium">@ternium</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/hsbc">@hsbc</a>)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="the-product">The product</h2>

<p>We set ourselves to create an autonomous data-driven optimization tool for time budgeting management.</p>

<p>The tool (Budgie) starts with a discovery phase of your expectations and needs. Then, as an exploration phase, it analyzes all your time habits and finally, assigns time slots in your calendar optimized for the objective you have set for yourself.</p>

<p>The last stage of followups, asks you if you were able to meet that time slot, to know the progress, and reschedule if necessary. This way, if you consistently fall short of your budget, it helps you rethink it so it’s attainable. Also, we create statistics about your progress in each time frame.</p>

<p>At its core, an optimizer finds the best time slots for you to leverage your time habits to make the most out of your time. A marketplace of connectors helps you to integrate the optimizer with the data sources that work best for you. Do you use Google Calendar? We’ve got you covered. Notion, ClickUp? That’s on the roadmap. Also, you don’t need to download anything: you can use our telegram bot, notion, or whatever you prefer to input your goals.</p>

<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final thoughts</h2>

<p>I really enjoyed the experience. We validate in less than 36hs that there is a real market with users who are willing to pay for Budgie to help meet their personal goals.</p>

<p>Feel free to reach out if you want to know more and/or tell us how you’d use it!</p>

<h2 id="reference-material">Reference material</h2>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o2DMFNwwjKc">[Spanish] Demo with pitch deck of Budgie</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Lucas Vittor</name><email>lvvittor@gmail.com</email></author><category term="english" /><category term="hackathon" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some weeks ago, Javier Mermet (a fellow data scientist and software engineer) and I participated in a team of two for the 36hs HackIT-BA Hackathon by ITBA Computer Society.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.lucasvittor.com/hack-itba-a-hackathon-with-great-people/mount_washington.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.lucasvittor.com/hack-itba-a-hackathon-with-great-people/mount_washington.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cómo funciona sobrevivir al ITBA</title><link href="https://www.lucasvittor.com/como-funciona-sobrevivir-al-itba/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cómo funciona sobrevivir al ITBA" /><published>2022-03-13T23:02:00-03:00</published><updated>2022-03-13T23:02:00-03:00</updated><id>https://www.lucasvittor.com/como-funciona-sobrevivir-al-itba</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.lucasvittor.com/como-funciona-sobrevivir-al-itba/"><![CDATA[<p>El ITBA no es fácil. La mayoría de nosotros vamos a pasar más de cinco años acá y cada experiencia es diferente</p>

<p>Ahora tengo hecho más del 50% de Ing. Informática y me estoy adelantando al plan de la carrera, con un promedio por encima de la media.</p>

<p>Mientras iba cursando me fui dando cuenta algunos hábitos que seguían los alumnos con mejores notas y aplicarlos me sirvió para estudiar menos y tener mejor rendimiento.</p>

<p>Esto es lo que yo necesitaba cuando estaba empezando la facultad y hoy se los quiero dejar como un manual para “hackear” al ITBA.</p>

<h2 id="recomendaciones-generales">Recomendaciones generales</h2>

<p><strong>Seguí el plan de la carrera, por algo esta así.</strong></p>

<p>Antes de que empiece el cuatrimestre, investigá cuáles son las materias más difíciles y ordená por nivel de dificultad. Dedicale más tiempo a estudiar las más difíciles: es importante que las guías estén al día.</p>

<p>Priorizá tener todo “aprobado” que muy buenas notas en algunas materias y re-cursar una: a largo plazo no hay diferencia entre un 6 y un 10.</p>

<p><strong>Las materias que estás cursando ya las cursó alguien antes. Buscá esas personas, preguntáles que temas conviene estudiar y cuáles no sirven.</strong></p>

<p>Buscá a alguien que esté un cuatrimestre adelantado (él tiene las cosas más recientes: pedile los TPs y parciales), otro que esté varios años delante (te va a dar recomendaciones sobre electivas, intercambios y profesores) y otro que ya se haya recibido (te va a servir para tener una visión más amplia de que cosas realmente sirven fuera de la facultad).</p>

<p><strong>Buscá las guías resueltas.</strong></p>

<p>Muchos profesores dicen que no las veas, pero la mayoría de la gente con buen promedio las ve. Te sirve para tener el “big picture” y entender cuales cosas sirven para el parcial.</p>

<p>Entendé que la idea idea es hacer las guías rápido para estar al día y poder resolver ejercicios de parciales.</p>

<p><strong>Hay veces que uno cree estar al día pero la realidad es otra.</strong></p>

<p>Conseguí un grupo de +5 amigos que sean más capaces que vos, estudiá con ellos.</p>

<p>Preguntales semanalmente cómo van con las guías y cerca de los exámenes (en general dos semanas antes) hagan parciales juntos.</p>

<p>SIEMPRE es una mala idea estudiar solo.</p>

<p><strong>Intenta tener apuntes compartidos con tus amigos.</strong></p>

<p>Tener un único apunte te va a asegurar dos cosas:</p>

<p>1) Vas a tener la misma base de estudio que tus otros amigos.</p>

<p>2) Vas a tener un apunte más completo porque lo hicieron varias personas.</p>

<p>Estos apuntes siempre complementalos con apuntes de cuatrimestres pasados.</p>

<p>Acordate la regla de oro: SIEMPRE hay uno que ya aprobó la materia que estás cursando, fijate cómo hizo.</p>

<p><strong>Si vivís lejos de la facultad repasá mientras estás en el transporte público.</strong></p>

<p>La idea es re-leer por arriba lo que aprendiste en el día. Hacerlo te va a permitir ver el big-picture de lo que dieron.</p>

<p><strong>Antes de empezar el cuatrimestre buscá los calendarios de las materias y fijate en que días se dan los temas.</strong></p>

<p>Yo los sincronizo con Google Calendar y antes de tener la clase leo los apuntes de cuatrimestres anteriores.</p>

<p>No importa leer al detalle, yo leo los títulos principales de lo que voy a ver. Después en la clase vas a entender mejor por qué parte de los conceptos del día vas y ya vas a estar preparado para lo que den.</p>

<p>Esta técnica sirve mucho si en general te aburrís en las clases: uno nunca sabe cuanto falta para terminar. Con esta nueva forma tenes un “índice mental” que vas tachando a medida que dan los temas.</p>

<h2 id="como-preparar-una-materia">Como preparar una materia</h2>

<p>Acá les dejo dos diagramas para que vean cómo estudio para la facultad.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="lo_que_te_dicen_que_hay_que_hacer.png" alt="Lo que te dicen que hay que hacer." />
  <figcaption>Lo que todo el mundo hace.</figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
  <img src="lo_que_hay_que_hacer.png" alt="Lo que hay que hacer." />
  <figcaption>Lo que yo hago para estudiar menos y que me vaya mejor.</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="lista-de-recursos-si-cursas-en-itba">Lista de recursos si cursas en ITBA</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/me_ITBA/">Reddit</a></p>

<p>Instagram</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/itbauniversidad/">Página Oficial</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/itbamemes/">itbamemes</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/ceitba/">ceitba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/itbajoneros/">itbajoneros</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/itba_gaming/">itba_gaming</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/asme.itba/">asme.itba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/embs.itba/">embs.itba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/brainware.itba/">brainware.itba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/itbafutbol/">itbafutbol</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/wie_itba/">wie_itba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/buddiesitba/">buddiesitba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/itbaglobal/">itbaglobal</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/itbabasquet/">itbabasquet</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/itba.love/">itba.love</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/aiche_itba/">aiche_itba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/computer.society.itba/">computer.society.itba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/itbadank/">itbadank</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/ieee.itba/">ieee.itba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/trama.itba/">trama.itba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/speitbasc/">speitbasc</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/mecanicaitba/">mecanicaitba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/memesitba/">memesitba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/graduadositba/">graduadositba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/turing.itba/">turing.itba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/itba_competicion/">itba_competicion</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/ajedrezitba/">ajedrezitba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/conexion.itba/">conexion.itba</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/techtrekar/">techtrekar</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Discord</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://discord.gg/EZsuanY7">Crypto Community ITBA</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://discord.gg/4FtcdVmP">ITBA Gaming</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://discord.gg/sCPUQXsW">Instituto Tecnológico de Buenos Aires</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Google Drive</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/0B-jdQcSzLnNVfjNWU0lEbXc4TUE2ZFFYRXlSV2RoOC1CcnAzWUM1QU9TQTRjYVh6Y1NIaEk?resourcekey=0-sDLiRLuBVz1uWn1Z8RYXTw&amp;usp=sharing">ITBA Informática</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/14Q34ulTsCxBPNgSG1dv4Q-Isqb3tSI2U?usp=sharing">Apuntes Tincho</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/137AUpxGFOfqPYj2U1dZm4zJosRejQAug?usp=sharing">Apuntes Britu</a></li>
</ul>

<p>La verdad son un monton más.</p>

<p>Una idea para mantener esta lista de recursos es tener esto actualizado es un github pages opensource con todos los links.</p>

<p>Si hay un par de informáticos manijas que les gusta la idea los puedo mentorear/ayudar con las tecnologías para hacerlo.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lucas Vittor</name><email>lvvittor@gmail.com</email></author><category term="spanish" /><category term="itba" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[El manual para sobrevivir al ITBA]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.lucasvittor.com/como-funciona-sobrevivir-al-itba/history_of_civilization_in_poland_by_jan_alojzy_matejko.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.lucasvittor.com/como-funciona-sobrevivir-al-itba/history_of_civilization_in_poland_by_jan_alojzy_matejko.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Workshop Way of Learning</title><link href="https://www.lucasvittor.com/the-workshop-way-of-learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Workshop Way of Learning" /><published>2022-01-29T03:05:00-03:00</published><updated>2022-01-29T03:05:00-03:00</updated><id>https://www.lucasvittor.com/the-workshop-way-of-learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.lucasvittor.com/the-workshop-way-of-learning/"><![CDATA[<p>Every single one of the folks working at tech knows that we will never stop learning. So, as a group, it’s important to understand what learning really is.</p>

<p>The best definition I found was from Earl C. Kelley:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>“We have not succeeded in answering all our problems. The answers we have found only serve to raise a whole set of new questions. In some ways, we feel we are as confused as ever, but we believe we are confused on a higher level and about more important things.”
— The Workshop Way of Learning (1951)</em></p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Lucas Vittor</name><email>lvvittor@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The definition of learning that I always use]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.lucasvittor.com/the-workshop-way-of-learning/at_the_waterfall_by_david_claypoole_johnston.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.lucasvittor.com/the-workshop-way-of-learning/at_the_waterfall_by_david_claypoole_johnston.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Simple sabotage startup manual</title><link href="https://www.lucasvittor.com/simple-sabotage-startup-manual/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Simple sabotage startup manual" /><published>2021-12-16T01:11:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-12-16T01:11:00-03:00</updated><id>https://www.lucasvittor.com/simple-sabotage-startup-manual</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.lucasvittor.com/simple-sabotage-startup-manual/"><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>OSS</strong> (now the <strong>CIA</strong>) once released a guide called <em>Simple Sabotage Field Manual</em> on how to sabotage an organization. That historical document was originally published in 1944, for use by <strong>OSS</strong> agents in motivating potential foreign saboteurs. The booklet contains instructions for destabilizing progress and productivity by non-violent means. Moreover, is separated into headings that correspond to specific audiences, including: “Organizations and Conferences”, “Managers and Supervisors” and “Employees”.</p>

<p>In this post, I want to extrapolate that manual to the startup environment. You should use this as a tool to detect red flags in your organization and a way to understand how to avoid getting there.</p>

<p>Think about this booklet as the <em>anti-agile</em> startup manifesto.</p>

<h2 id="organizations-and-conferences">Organizations and Conferences</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Insist on doing everything through “channels”. <strong><em>Never permit short-cuts to be taken in order to, expedite decisions.</em></strong></li>
  <li>Make “speeches”. <strong><em>Talk as frequently as possible and at great length</em></strong>. <strong><em>Illustrate your “points” by long anecdotes and accounts of personal experiences</em></strong>. Never hesitate to make a few appropriate “patriotic” comments.</li>
  <li>When possible, refer all matters to committees, for “further study and consideration”. <strong><em>Attempt to make the committees as large as possible - never less than five.</em></strong></li>
  <li><strong><em>Bring up irrelevant issues as frequently as possible.</em></strong></li>
  <li>Haggle over precise wordings of communications, minutes, resolutions.</li>
  <li><strong><em>Refer back to matters decided upon at the last meeting and attempt to reopen the question of the advisability of that decision.</em></strong></li>
  <li>Advocate “caution”. Be “reasonable” and urge your fellow-conferees to be “reasonable” and avoid haste which might result in embarrassments or difficulties later on.</li>
  <li><strong><em>Be worried about the propriety of any decision.</em></strong> Raise the question of whether such action as is contemplated lies within the jurisdiction of the group or whether it might conflict with the policy of some higher echelon.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="managers-and-supervisors">Managers and Supervisors</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Demand written orders.</li>
  <li><strong><em>“Misunderstand” orders. Ask endless questions or engage in long correspondence about such orders.</em></strong></li>
  <li><strong><em>Do everything possible to delay the delivery of orders</em></strong>. Even though parts of an order may be ready beforehand, <strong><em>don’t deliver it until it is completely ready.</em></strong></li>
  <li><strong><em>Don’t order new working materials until your current stocks have been virtually exhausted</em></strong> so that the slightest delay in filling your order will mean a shutdown.</li>
  <li><strong><em>Order high-quality materials which are hard to get.</em></strong> If you don’t get them argue about it. Warn that inferior materials will mean inferior work.</li>
  <li>In making work assignments, <strong><em>always sign out the unimportant jobs first</em></strong>. See that the important jobs are assigned to inefficient workers of poor machines.</li>
  <li><strong><em>Insist on perfect work in relatively unimportant products</em></strong>; send back for refinishing those which have the least flaw. Approve other defective parts whose flaws are not visible to the naked eye.</li>
  <li>Make mistakes in routing so that parts and materials will be sent to the wrong place in the plant.</li>
  <li><strong><em>When training new workers, give incomplete or misleading instructions.</em></strong></li>
  <li><strong><em>To lower morale and with it, production, be pleasant to inefficient workers; give them undeserved promotions.</em></strong> Discriminate against efficient workers; complain unjustly about their work.</li>
  <li><strong><em>Hold conferences when there is more critical work to be done.</em></strong></li>
  <li><strong><em>Multiply paperwork in plausible ways.</em></strong></li>
  <li>Multiply the procedures and clearances involved in issuing instructions, paychecks, and so on. <strong><em>See that three people have to approve everything where one would do.</em></strong></li>
  <li><strong><em>Apply all regulations to the last letter.</em></strong></li>
</ol>

<h2 id="employees">Employees</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Work slowly. <strong><em>Think out ways to increase the number of movements necessary on your job.</em></strong></li>
  <li><strong><em>Contrive as many interruptions to your work as you can</em></strong>.</li>
  <li>Even if you understand the language <strong><em>pretend to not to understand</em></strong> instructions in a foreign tongue.</li>
  <li>Pretend that instructions are hard to understand, and ask to have them repeated more than once. Or <strong><em>pretend that you are particularly anxious to do your work, and pester the foreman with unnecessary questions.</em></strong></li>
  <li><strong><em>Do your work poorly and blame it on bad tools, machinery, or equipment. Complain that these things are preventing you from doing your job right.</em></strong></li>
  <li><strong><em>Never pass on your skill and experience to a new or less skillful worker.</em></strong></li>
  <li><strong><em>Snarl up administration in every possible way</em></strong>. Fill out forms illegible so that they will have to be done over; make mistakes or omit requested information in forms.</li>
  <li>If possible, join or help organize a group for presenting employee problems to the management.</li>
  <li>Misroute materials.</li>
  <li><strong><em>Mix good parts with unusable scrap and rejected parts.</em></strong></li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Lucas Vittor</name><email>lvvittor@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Simple sabotage startup manual: the anti-agile startup manifesto.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.lucasvittor.com/simple-sabotage-startup-manual/the_miracle_of_the_lame_man_healed_by_saint_peter_and_saint_john.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.lucasvittor.com/simple-sabotage-startup-manual/the_miracle_of_the_lame_man_healed_by_saint_peter_and_saint_john.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>